(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Planet Of Giants
(Doctor Who 1963 S02E01 Whopix fan edit)
巨人星球
(《神秘博士》老版 Whopix 粉丝剪辑版）
（基于 opensubtitles.org 上英文字幕翻译）
（中文翻译: 巴蛮子sz )
（注意: 本字幕不针对原版视频, 而是Whopix粉丝剪辑版)
http://wp.me/p1mHFo-11b
We're approaching a planet.
我们正在向一个星球靠拢
Which one?
哪个星球？
We shall soon see.
很快就能知道
Ow.
噢
What's the matter my dear?
怎么回事, 亲爱的？
I burnt myself on the console.
我被控制台烫了一下
Oh, something overheating here.
Just as well we're landing?
哦, 什么东西过热了, 就在我们着陆的时候
Susan, check the fault locator please.
苏珊, 请检查一下故障定位器
Yes Grandfather.
好的爷爷
We're not going to blow
up or anything, are we?
我们不会爆炸什么的吧, 会吗？
Oh no no no, of course not.
噢, 不不不, 当然不会
It's just, well, there we were
in the late eighteenth century
只是, 这个, 之前我们在18世纪晚期的时候
and I tried another frequency to sidestep the ship
back into the middle of the twentieth century.
我尝试了另一个频率, 将船绕回到20世纪中期
GRANDFATHER, THE DOORS, THEY'RE OPENING!
爷爷, 门, 自己开了！
What's happening... Unbelievable!
怎么回事...难以置信！
Chesterton close the doors please! We haven't materialised properly! Quickly!
切斯特顿请把门关上！我们还没有正确完成实体化！快点！
- What do you mean close the doors?
- Don't argue dear boy
- 什么意思, “关上门”？  - 别跟我争论, 孩子
it's an emergency, close the doors!
Quick! Use force!
情况危急, 去关上门！快！用力啊！
Is everything alright?
一切都还好吗？
We're just landing.
我们刚刚着陆了
Are you alright Doctor?
你还好吧, 博士？
.....what?
...什么？
Are you alright?
你还好吗？
Oh please, don't bother me!
哦, 拜托, 不要打扰我
What happened just then?
刚才发生了什么事？
Susan, go back to the fault locator,
苏珊, 回去看看故障定位器
and I want you to check everything,
child you understand, EVERYTHING!
而且我要你检查每样东西, 孩子你明白吗, 每样东西！
Well at least we seem to be alright.
还好, 至少我们似乎都没事
Mm? Oh don't be childish, they opened!
嗯？哦别这么幼稚了, 门打开过了！
The doors opened before
we had properly materialised!
门打开了, 在我们还没完全实体化之前！
But what does it mean?
但那又意味着什么？
Hah-ah!
啊哈！
Doctor, you needn't keep it a secret from us!
博士, 你没有必要对我们保密!
What?
什么？
Doctor, don't keep us in suspense.
博士, 别让我们心里打鼓
Oh don't go on with these futile questions, please!
噢, 不要继续问这些无用的问题, 拜托！
Can't you understand, can't you see?!
你不明白吗, 你看不到吗？!
No we can't - that's just it!
不, 我们不能 - 就这个！
Oh we were just about to materialise
when the doors opened
唉, 我们正要实体化, 这时候门打开了
and we hadn't properly adjusted!
我们还没有做出相应调整！
You mean something went out of the ship?
你是说有什么东西跑出去了？
No that's impossible!
不, 那是不可能的！
Came inside then?
那就是跑进来了？
Oh please, don't keep talking
on the twentieth-century level!
噢, 拜托, 不要再在20世纪的水平上说话
I'm talking about time-travel!
我在说的是时间旅行！
Neither of you can understand what
I'm talking about, I can s-see that!
你们没一个人能懂我在说什么, 我算是明白了！
How could we, you've
never explained it to us!
我们怎么能懂, 你都从来没有跟我们解释过！
- My dear boy...
- Grandfather everything's alright!
- 小伙子...  - 爷爷, 一切都很正常！
There isn't a fault anywhere,
not even on yellow standby!
任何地方都没有故障, 即使是黄色备用系统也没有!
But there must be something wrong, Susan!
但肯定有什么地方出错了, 苏珊！
I shall have to check that fault locator
myself to make sure, excuse me...
我还是得自己去检查故障定位器, 保险起见, 失陪...
Oh I do wish he wouldn't talk in riddles!
哦, 我真希望他不要说谜语！
So do I. Susan perhaps you can help us?
我也是. 苏珊, 也许你可以帮我们一下？
I just know that the most dangerous
moment is at the point of materialisation.
我只是知道最危险的时候就是实体化这个时刻了
Nothing's ever happened to us before.
以前我们什么都没发生过
Well the doors have never
opened like that before.
这门以前也从来没有这样打开过
Well, happily no harm's been done. It's most puzzling.
好吧, 很高兴没有造成任何伤害. 这事非常令人费解
Oh my dear Barbara was I rude to you just now?
哦, 亲爱的芭芭拉, 刚才我太凶了吧？
If so, I'm so sorry. I always
forget the niceties under pressure.
如果是, 我很抱歉. 一有压力我总是忘记风度
- Please forgive me.
- There's nothing to forgive.
- 请原谅我 - 没什么关系
Thank you. Hm.. Hah!
谢谢你. 嗯...哈！
Well I suppose everything's alright. And yet, er...
好吧, 我估计一切都正常. 还有...
See the temperature there is perfectly...
it's quite safe to go outside.
看外面的温度很合适...去外面相当安全
Oh Susan, just turn on the scanner a
minute, let's try and see where we are.
苏珊, 把监视器打开一下, 我们看看我们在哪儿
Doctor!
博士！
Perhaps you need a new tube Doctor?
也许你需要一个新的显像管(:-), 博士
Did you notice the way it blew out?
你注意到爆炸的方式了吗？
It was like an internal explosion.
感觉像是一个内爆
Yes, like, like ehh...something
too big for it's frame!
感觉像是...什么东西太大了撑破了
Yes.
是的
And yet, I don't know...
That can't be right!
但是, 我不知道...那不可能！
What do we do now Doctor? Take
the scanner out and strip it down?
我们现在怎么办博士？把监视器拿出来, 把它剥掉？
Oh no no no, dear boy. No.
It's most puzzling of course,
噢, 不不不, 乖孩子, 不要. 这事当然很让人不解
but now we don't know what's behind those doors.
但现在我们不知道门后面有什么
Well we must go outside and look.
You said it was quite safe...
那我们必须出去看一看, 你说过外面很安全...
Yes...I wonder why the..? Well, we must see.
是的...很奇怪为什么...好吧, 我们必须看看
- Shall I open the doors Grandfather?
- Er, yes please Susan.
- 那我打开门了, 爷爷  - 呃, 好, 打开吧苏珊
But all of you, cautiously please!
但你们所有人, 都务必小心！
Doctor, what made the doors open before?
博士, 之前是什么把门打开了？
The space pressure was far too great
whilst we were materialising.
我们在实体化的时候, 太空压力过于巨大了
The strange thing is that
we all came out of it unscathed!
奇怪的是, 我们都毫发无损地过来了!
Hah, it's, it's most puzzling,
it's a big mystery my boy, come along...
哈, 这是最令人费解的, 这是一个很大的谜, 孩子, 快来..
It's like a mountain pass or something.
这里像是一个山口什么的
Now why wouldn't the scanner
show us all this mm?
为什么监视器不告诉我们这些？
Perhaps that was the only damage to the ship, Doctor.
也许, 那是对船的唯一破坏, 博士
Overloading on the scanner circuits.
让监视器线路过载了
Yes, I suppose so, it could be...
是, 我想是, 有可能..
What a strange rock formation!
多么奇怪的岩层啊!
Yes, it is, isn't it?
是, 的确, 是吧？
There are two different types of rock. Doctor?
这里有两种类型的石头, 博士？
Mm?
嗯？
Look... This is ordinary stone up here,
看...上面这里是普通的石头
but this down here seems to be quite different.
但下面这种就有很大不同
Chesterton, here. Come here,
look here. Is that cement? Heh.
切斯特顿, 过来, 到这里来. 看这个, 这是水泥吧
Might be.
可能是
Rather a rough kind isn't it?
很硬的那种, 对不？
Mn, very rough. They look like
pebbles of sand don't they?
嗯, 非常硬. 它们看起来像鹅卵石, 不是吗？
Yes, yes as a matter of fact
it's in a way to hold the stone in place.
是的, 事实上, 这在某种程度上是为了把石头固定好
You know, to fix it firmly beneath!
知道吧, 把它牢牢固定在底下
I would have thought the stone was
heavy enough to keep itself in place.
我还以为这块石头足够重, 可以保持自己的位置
Yes, it's all most odd
isn't it? Most odd...
是的, 这一切很奇怪, 是吧？最奇怪的是...
Now Barbara, I suggest that you and I take that path,
芭芭拉, 我建议你和我挑这条路
and Susan and you sir, er, go that way, mm?
而苏珊和先生你, 走那条路, 嗯？
Yes alright, but stay within calling distance,
行吧, 但保持在通话距离内
and you see anything sing out. We'll do the same.
你们看到什么东西就喊出来. 我们也会这样
Yes, yes, yes... Mmm.
好, 好, 好...嗯
Mm...
唔
Now take this rock here,
it's most extraordinary...
现在拿这个石头来说, 它就非常不寻常...
Doctor! Doctor, it's a huge snake!
博士, 博士, 这有条巨蛇！
What, eh?
什么？
Let's call the others.
我们把其他人叫来
Oh, er, wait wait wait...
Yes, I-I I think it's dead.
哦, 等等, 等等. 是了, 我想这是死的
Ian! Look at this.
伊恩！看这个
That's odd. I suppose it couldn't
be an egg, hah. Not that size.
这很稀奇. 我想它不会是个蛋, 哈！没有那么大的
There are more of them over there, look.
那边还有更多, 看
Yeah. Ostrich?
是啊, 鸵鸟的？
It would have been rounder than this.
那应该会比这圆些
There are dozens of them over here!
There's a whole pile of them!
这里有好多！有一整堆呢！
Oh! Ian, Ian!
啊！伊恩, 伊恩！
It is dead isn't it?
这是死的吧？
Yes. It's dead alright - stiff as a poker.
是了, 它是死的, 没事 - 僵硬得跟扑克一样
What a fantastic size!
这么大的个头！
Yes.
是
It's a giant ant.
这是只巨蚁
It is like it isn't he? It looks as
if it was trying to carry these eggs.
它就像...看起来它好像是想搬运这些卵
Yes, well that's natural behaviour for an ant,
是的, 这对蚂蚁来说是自然的反应
when it's attacked, take the eggs to safety.
当它受到攻击时, 就把卵带到安全的地方去
The worker ant would give his life
rather than abandon the eggs you know...
工蚁会献出自己的生命, 而不是放弃蚁卵, 你知道吗...
Well he couldn't have had
much of a chance could he?
他不可能有太多机会, 对吧？
I mean he must have died quickly.
我是说他一定很快就死了
Yeah... All these eggs scattered about.
是的...所有这些蚁卵都散落一地
Other ants must have been frightened away.
其他蚂蚁一定被吓跑了
I wonder what sort of a world
could produce an insect that size?
我想知道什么样的世界能产生这么大的昆虫？
Well here we are then, this is the tail end of it, and I know what it is.
好, 我们到这里了, 这是它的尾部, 而且我知道这是什么了
- It's a huge earthworm.
- What?
- 这是一只巨型蚯蚓  - 什么？
Yes, there are no earthworms
this size on your planet.
是的, 在你们的星球上没有这么大的蚯蚓
You're right there aren't!
你说得对, 没有
know except for it's size, I would
swear that it came from your world.
要知道不考虑它的大小的话, 我得发誓它来自你们的世界
However, lets..er, let's go on. Come along.
但是, 我们..呃, 我们继续. 一起来吧
Now this is really baffling!
现在这真的很令人费解！
A huge picture of Night Scented Stock!
一幅紫罗兰的巨大图片!
Yes it is, but why put up a picture of it? I don't get it.
的确是, 但为什么竖一幅它的图片？我搞不懂
Ah, some writing there... "Alf's Seed Company, Norwich!"
啊, 这里有些文字：“Alf 种子公司, 诺威奇”
Norwich! That's England isn't it? Norfolk!
诺威奇！那属于英格兰的对不？诺福克郡的！
Yes, it is. Susan, this
means we're on Earth!
是啊, 真的, 苏珊. 这就意味着我们在地球上
Something's very odd here,
first those ants, now this.
这里有些东西非常奇怪, 先是那些蚂蚁, 现在是这个
Hey, look at the end
of that, it's all charred!
嘿, 看这末端, 全都碳化了!
Yes, you can see quite clearly
what this is. It's a matchstick.
是的, 你可以很清楚地看到这是什么东西. 它是一根火柴
Well it certainly looks like one.
嗯, 看起来应该是
No, it just doesn't look
like one, it is a matchstick.
不, 不只是看起来是, 它就是一根火柴
What, that size?!
什么, 那么大？
Don't you see, that huge earthworm and now this?
你没明白吗, 那个巨型蚯蚓, 现在又这个？
Can't you see what's happened Mm?
你没明白是怎么回事, 嗯？
Look at this matchbox!
看这个火柴盒！
It must be an exhibition Susan, something like the world fair.
这一定是一个展览, 苏珊, 有点像世界博览会
- Things this size...
- No Ian.
- 都是这么大的东西  - 不是, 伊恩
Well what else? look
at the scale of things!
那还能是什么？看看这些东西的规模！
You're wrong Ian, completely wrong!
你错了, 伊恩, 完全错了!
I-I thought just now that something was
wrong when I saw that, but now I'm sure.
我刚才看到那个时, 以为是什么东西出了问题, 但现在我确定了
Alright, what's your theory then?
好吧, 那你的结论是什么？
That these things haven't been made
bigger, we've been made smaller!
那就是, 这些东西没有变大, 而是我们变小了!
Smaller?!
变小了？
We have been reduced roughly
to the size of an inch!
我们已经被缩小到大约一英寸的尺度!
An inch?!
一英寸？！
Mm. You, me, all of us, and the ship!
嗯. 你, 我, 我们所有人, 还有飞船!
We must get hold of the others
quickly and return to the TARDIS!
我们必须迅速找到其他人, 返回到 TARDIS!
- What's that?
- What is it?
- 什么声音？  - 是什么？
Run Susan, run!
跑, 苏珊, 快跑！
- Look out!
- Urgh!
- 小心！ - 啊！
Yeah.. Well it looks a
tremendous distance to me.
好了...唔, 在我看来这有好长一段距离
There's a house over there, and there's
a man sitting down reading something.
远处有一栋房子, 还有一个人坐在那里阅读什么东西
It's a notebook I think.
是个笔记本, 我想
- Did he have the matchbox?
- How do I know?!
- 是他拿了火柴盒吗？  - 我怎么知道？
I don't know how you know,
but you surprise me sometimes.
我不知道你怎么能知道, 但你时不时会给我们些意外
Yes, I suppose so. Look, watch
what you're doing will you?!
嗯, 估计是. 嘿, 小心一点行不？
Look, Doctor give us some hope, I
mean, Ian's inside that matchbox!
博士, 给我们点希望吧, 我是说, 伊恩在那个火柴盒里面！
Gently, gently gently!
轻点, 轻点轻点！
We've got to find Chesterton!
我们得找到切斯特顿！
But Grandfather, supposing the
man walks off with the matchbox!
但是爷爷, 假设那个人拿着火柴盒走了呢？
Have courage my dear! I know that
all of this is a bit of a nightmare,
有点勇气, 亲爱的! 我知道这一切都有点像是噩梦
but we've just got to get Ian back
and then we can go back to the ship.
但我们得把伊恩找回来, 然后我们就可以回船上去了
And then can you get
us back to normal size?
然后你能让我们恢复正常的大小吗？
But of course, yes I'll try!
There's always a chance!
当然了, 我会试试, 总应该有可能的！
But first things first, we must find Chesterton
但事有先后, 我们必须先找到切斯特顿
It's Mr Forester isn't it?
We spoke on the telephone...
是弗瑞思特先生是吗？我们在电话里说过话...
Yes, I got here as quickly as I could.
I hope you haven't taken any action yet?
是的, 我尽快地赶过来了. 我期望你还没有采取什么行动吧？
Not yet, but I have written my report.
还没有, 但我已经写好报告了
You do realise what's at stake here Mr Farrow?
你知道这样会有什么后果吧, 法柔先生？
The early experiments were noted
by the ministry, welcomed in fact!
早期实验结果已经在部里备案了, 事实上反响不错啊！
I've already geared factories, advertising
and all the rest of it to start pushing DN6.
我已经联系好了工厂、广告商这些, 要开始推DN6了
I'm sorry about that, but I can't
give you the approval that you want.
对此我很抱歉, 但我不能给出你想要的批准书
I see.
我明白了
You're aware of course that if it doesn't
go into production I shall be completely ruined?
你当然也知道, 如果它不投产, 我就会彻底破产？
That is very unfortunate, but really, you
should have waited till we gave you the go-ahead!
那真的很不幸, 但真的, 你应该等我们点了头再开始的！
Well that's all very well,
but it doesn't help me does it?
话倒是没错, 但这对我已经没帮助了是吧
Surely we can work something out?
也许我们可以想点什么办法？
There's a fortune to be made out of this...
可以借此赚上一笔...
I don't think I want to go
on with this conversation.
我觉得我不想再继续这场谈话了
Do you know why I am a success Mr Farrow?
你知道我为什么是一个成功者吗, 法柔先生？
Because I've never allowed
the word "can't" to exist
因为我从来不允许“不能”这个词存在
There's always a way, always!
总是有办法的, 总是！
Not this time.
这次没有
This isn't business, this is science,
the formulae is unacceptable
这不是生意, 这是科学, 这个配方是不可接受的！
And I can't and I do mean can't Mr Forester,
allow DN6 to go into production!
我不能, 说了就是不能, 弗瑞斯特先生, 允许让DN6投产!
Now I'll make that phone call.
现在我要去给部里打电话了
Just a moment!
等一下！
I think It's dead.
我觉得它死了
But it could still sting!
但它还是可能蜇人！
Mm. Hah-ha! What an awe-inspiring sight!
唔, 哈哈！多么令人敬畏的景象！
Now what chance would
human-beings have, I really wonder,
人类还有什么机会, 我很好奇
in a world of creatures like this bee, mm?
这世界的生物要都像这蜜蜂这样的话, 嗯？
None at all!
一点机会没有！
Little closer look...
稍微近一点看...
Well I haven't taken my eyes off it
Grandfather, it hasn't even trembled.
我没把眼挪开过, 爷爷, 它连抖一下都没有
It seems you're right, it is dead.
看来你是对的, 它是死的
The same distinctive aroma!
同样的一种香精味
Yes, I've noticed it on
all the other dead things.
是的, 我在其它的死亡生物上面也注意到了
Well that must be what's killing them then.
那可能就是那个东西杀死了它们！
I wonder what would want to
kill off nature like this?
我很好奇什么东西想要杀死这些自然生物呢？
Well what worries me is
all the different things it's killing.
让我担心的是, 它可以杀死这么多不同的生物
Things that fly in the air,
things that move on the ground...
天上飞的, 地上走的...
things that move under the ground.
So indiscriminate.
地底爬的, 全不放过
- Doctor?
- Mm?
- 博士？  - 嗯?
Whatever it is that's killing these
things... Could it kill us too?
不管是什么东西杀死了这些东西...它也能杀死我们吗？
Well, we must presume that it can.
是啊, 我们必须认定它能
So no eating or drinking until we've
done our very best to find Ian mm?
所以不要吃喝东西, 我们竭尽所能找到伊恩, 嗯？
(A roaring boom momentarily
splits through the heady silence.)
He's been shot dead.
他被枪杀了
- Are you sure he is dead?
- Oh yes
- 你肯定他已经死了  - 哦, 是的
Nothing but death all around us!
我们周围没有别的, 全是死亡！
Yes, what's happening here?
是, 到底发生了什么？
You weren't with us Chesterton, but
every insect we came across was dead.
你刚才没跟我们在一起, 切斯特顿, 但我们路过的每个昆虫都死了
Yes, Susan and I saw a
great many huge dead ants.
是啊, 苏珊和我看到了好多死去的巨型蚂蚁
Everything else was the same, Ian.
其它的所有东西也是一样, 伊恩
Yes, and we don't know
what it is that killed them.
是, 而且我们不知道是什么东西杀死了它们
But that man, he's been shot. Murdered!
但那个人, 他是被枪杀的, 谋杀！
But who'd kill insects in
a perfectly ordinary garden?
但谁会杀死一座普通花园里面所有的昆虫呢？
I mean pests one can understand, but...
我觉得要是害虫还可理解, 但是...
Surely it's wrong to kill bees
and worms and things isn't it?
杀死蜜蜂、蚯蚓这些显然是不对的, 是吧？
Quite so. Both are vital
to the growth of things.
的确是, 它们对于植物生长都很重要
However, we must leave this little
mystery and get back to the ship.
不管怎样, 我们必须撇下这个不解之谜, 返回到飞船去
As I said my dear, it's fortunate
for all of us that everything is dead...
如我所说, 亲爱的, 所有东西都死了也算我们幸运...
Argh! Grandfather!
啊！爷爷！
Don't move, any of you.
别动, 任何人
And whatever you do,
don't look into the cat's eyes.
而且不管你们怎么做, 不要看猫的眼睛
Close your own if you want to.
想闭眼睛的话就闭上
Doctor, I think the cat's losing interest.
博士, 我觉得这猫失去兴趣了
Don't relax! One swipe of it's paw
would smash us to pieces!
别放松！猫爪挥一下就能把我们撕成碎片！
Well we can't get back to the ship just
yet, and you know how fast cats can move.
看来我们暂时还不能回飞船, 你知道猫能跑多快的
And another thing, we could be mistaken for mice
还有一个问题是, 我们可能会被错当成老鼠
and I don't fancy being part of the cat's diet!
我可不喜欢变成猫的美餐！
Oh it gets more horrifying every moment!
噢, 一刻比一刻变得恐怖了！
Look, couldn't we make contact
with the people here somehow?
对了, 我们不能跟这里的人取得某种联系吗？
No, I'm afraid not.
不, 我觉得不能
Well why not, they might be able to help us.
为什么不, 他们也许能帮上我们
It's out of the question my dear,
how could we possibly communicate with them?
这是不可能的, 亲爱的, 我们怎么能与他们交流呢？
Imagine a record played
at the wrong speed, Susan.
想想一张唱片，以错误速度播放着, 苏珊
We'd sound like a little squeak to them,
and they'd sound like a low growl to us.
对他们来说我们的声音就是悉悉索索, 他们对我们就是低吼
Anyway, even if we could communicate,
what would they do to us?
而且, 就算我们能交流, 他们又能帮我们做什么？
We're freaks. They'd put us in a glass case
我们是怪人, 他们会把我们放到玻璃瓶子里面
and examine us through a microscope!
用显微镜来观察我们！
Oh that's a thought isn't it.
哦, 那只是个猜测, 对不？
And I would add another
and more important factor.
我还可以补充一个更加重要的因素
The people that live in this house
are murderers, or one of them is.
住在这个房子里面的人是杀人犯, 至少有一个是
Therefore, we can't expect
sympathy and understanding
所以, 我们不能指望获得同情与理解
from an insane or a criminal mind!
从一个疯子或者罪犯那里！
Yes, what about that dead man?
对. 这个死人怎么办？
Oughtn't we to do something about it?
我们是不是应该做点什么？
Well what can we do my dear? I
mean, surely this is the question.
我们能做什么呢, 亲爱的？我是说, 这的确是一个问题
Normally I wouldn't hesitate, but the
destruction of the life-force is frightful,
通常来说我不会犹豫, 毕竟生命的逝去是很可怕的
but there it is! I mean, what can we do as we are?
但已然发生了(?). 我是说, 我们这样子能做什么呢？
Well, I can't see any sign of that cat,
however much safety that gives us.
好了, 我没见到那只猫的影子了, 也许这能让我们觉得安全点
Well, shall we proceed?
那, 我们继续？
I can see a huge leg coming, run!
我看见一条巨腿走过来了, 快跑！
This...this way!
这...这边！
- No, Barbara
- Go on, Susan!
- 不, 芭芭拉  - 走啊, 苏珊！
- I'd like to help you, Ian.
- Go on!
- 我想帮你们一下, 伊恩  - 走！
- Sorry!
- It's alright. This way, quickly!
- 抱歉！  - 没事, 这边, 快！
Oh, Grandfather, they're overstepping on us!
哦, 爷爷, 它们要踩到我们了！
Oh they're alright, they're alright. It's
a pity they didn't come this way though.
没事了, 没事了. 很遗憾他们俩没有朝这边过来
Well shall we go over to them?
那, 我们去他们那边吧？
No, no, it's dangerous!
Let's go over to that pipe there!
不, 不, 太危险了！我们到那条管子那里去！
Come on Barbara, get out of
here before it moves again.
快点芭芭拉, 赶紧出来, 否则一会儿又移动了
- Oh...that was worse than the big dipper.
- It was.
- 噢...这比过山车还难受  - 的确
You know we were lucky this case was full.
要知道我们还是幸运的, 这个包比较满
Course, it had to happen to us,
of all the places to pick, hah,
是啊, 那么多地方可以去, 偏偏让我们赶上了, 哈
we had to choose one that was movable!
我们还非得选一个会移动的！
Have you any idea where we are?
你清楚我们在什么地方吗？
That's a ceiling up there.
那上面有个天花板
That means we're indoors and
the Doctor and Susan are outside.
这意味着我们在户内, 而博士和苏珊在外面
Let's move the body.
我们来搬尸体吧
Where can we put him?
我们能把他放哪儿？
In a store room.
放储藏室去
They've gone
他们走了
It's much better when they're
a long way away, isn't it?
还是让他们走远一点更好, 对吧？
Are you sure you saw one of
them pick up the briefcase
你确定你看见他们中的一个拿起了公文包？
and go into that building behind us?
走进了我们后面那栋房子？
Well I definitely saw him pick up the briefcase.
我绝对看见他拿起了公文包
Well when he walked past us it was
just like a mountain, just a blur, you know.
嗯, 当他走过我们时, 就像一座山, 很模糊, 你知道吗
But he must have gone inside the house!
但他一定是走进了那栋房子!
Careful Grandfather, well
don't fall down there will you?
小心点爷爷, 别掉下去了, 好吗？
Oh-hah-Ooh POO! FAWF! An awful
smell of chemical in there!
噢-哈-噢-噗, 里面一股难闻的化学品味道！
Oh yes.
哦, 真是
Foof! Oh, hm.
呼！噢, 嗯
It's not just an ordinary drainpipe is it?
这不是一根普通的排水管, 对吧？
Now, I wonder if that pipe extends into
the room where that briefcase went.
现在, 我在想那根管子是不是也通到房子里, 就是公文包所去的房子
Are you thinking of climbing up the inside of it?
你在考虑从里面爬上去？
Yes, yes of course my dear,
there's no other way.
是的, 当然是, 亲爱的, 没有其它的办法
If you go in there you'll see it's all corroded
so there's plenty of hand and foot holds.
如果你进去就可以看到全都腐蚀了, 所有有很多地方可以搭手脚
And that chemical smell means that it's germ free.
而且那种化学品味道就意味着里面没有细菌
Oh, but it's too far for you grandfather!
哦, 但对你来说这太远了, 爷爷！
Well If it is, then I shall have to give up,
and I'm not going to give up before I've tried.
如果是, 那我就不得不放弃, 但我不打算还没尝试就放弃
And remember you must think of the other two,
记住你得替另外两个人考虑
They must be constantly reminding
themselves
they're only one inch high!
你必须不断地提醒自己, 他们只有一英寸高!
There's only the two of us to help them!
这里只有我们两个可以帮助他们！
- Alright, but you let me go first.
- Yes-yes, yes go-on.../
- 好吧, 但你得让我走前面  - 好, 好, 走...
Ian look at this!
伊恩, 看这个！
Mm, yeah.
嗯, 嘢
What do you suppose it is, corn, wheat?
你觉得这是什么, 玉米, 麦子？
Wheat.
麦子
Still haven't thought of a way
of getting out of this place...
还是没有想到一个办法走出这个地方...
Oh yes, you're right it is wheat.
哦是的, 你说对了, 这是麦子
Ooh, it's all covered in some
sticky stuff, like toffee.
喔, 外面都包了一层粘稠的东西, 像是太妃糖
Hey Barbara, look at this...
嘿芭芭拉, 看这个...
Give me your handkerchief will you?
把你的手绢给我, 好吗？
Do you see what this is?
A book of litmus papers, hah!
你明白这是什么吗？一叠石蕊试纸, 哈！
How often have I held a piece of
litmus paper in my fingers..?
我经常将一叠石蕊试纸捏在手指间
- Oh well, it's a handy seat.
- Yeah
- 好吧, 这变成一个方便的座位了  - 是啊
You realise what this place is?
你明白这是什么地方吗？
Ooh it's some sort of a laboratory.
哦, 这是一间实验室
Yes, I think it must explain
those dead insects and things.
是的, 我想这可以解释那些死亡的昆虫
They must be doing some experiments.
他们肯定在做某种实验
Course it makes it all
the more dangerous for us.
这就使得所有东西都对我们更加危险了
Why do you say that?
你怎么这么说？
Well, whatever killed those
insects could easily kill us.
这样, 杀死那些昆虫的东西, 也能轻易杀死我们
The Doctor said something
like that, I... I'd forgotten.
博士说过类似的话, 我...我都忘记了
Well don't touch anything, eh?
嗯, 别碰任何东西, 嗯？
But...but...Ian...
但是...但是...伊恩...
I mean, look at the way these seeds
are coated. They're obviously samples.
我是说, 看看这些种子外面的涂层, 它们显然都是样品
Yes, I think they must be
inventing a new insecticide
是了, 我想他们是在创造一种新的杀虫剂
and they've sprayed these seeds with it.
而且他们把它喷到这些种子上了
Oh surely I... I mean, couldn't
it be just preserving oil?
哦, 当然我...我是说, 那就不可能只是保护油？
I doubt it, anyway, you keep away from it.
我表示怀疑. 不管怎样, 你离它远点
I-AN! BAR-BARA!
伊恩！芭芭拉！
There they are, can you see them Barbara?
他们在那儿, 你看到他们了吗芭芭拉？
Doctor, Susan we're up here!
博士, 苏珊, 我们在上面！
- Hello up there!
- What uncanny good luck!
- 上面的人你们好！  - 不可思议的好运啊！
Oh ha-ha Grandfather, we've found them!
哦, 哈哈, 爷爷, 我们能找到他们了！
Yes, I know my dear, I know!
是的, 我知道, 亲爱的, 我知道
Did they really climb up that sink pipe?
他们真的从那根下水管道爬上来了？
Yeah, they must have done.
I wonder if we can get down it?
是, 他们肯定是. 我在想我们能否下去？
Climb down the plug-chain, to us!
从链子爬下来, 到我们这里来！
Yes alright we will!
好的, 我们下来！
Here, it's about thirty feet or thereabouts,
do you think you can make it?
这差不多有30多英尺, 你觉得你能完成吗？
Yes, I'll make it somehow, it'll
be worth it to see them two again.
是, 我能完成. 能见到他们俩, 这是值得的
Alright, let me go first.
好吧, 我先来
You been over doing things.
你体力有点透支了
Yes... Yes, I-I think I have.
是的...是的, 我想我是
I'll go and get you some water
you know it'll freshen you up, eh?
我去给你弄点水, 可以让你精神一点, 嗯？
Thank you
谢谢你
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
- I want your handkerchief. I was going...
- No!
- 我想拿手绢, 正要  - 不！
- What's the matter?
- You can't have it,
- 怎么啦？  - 你不能拿它
You mustn't touch it!
你不许碰它！
Barbara!
芭芭拉！
No-one must touch...
谁也不许碰...
Barbara!
芭芭拉！
There, it's the same aroma! Insecticide.
You didn't eat or drink anything?
这里, 同样的香精味！杀虫剂！你们没乱吃乱喝什么吧？
Well no, certainly not!
嗯没有, 当然没有
Shes got insecticide on her hands, she touched it.
她手上有杀虫剂, 她摸过了
Well she never told me,
I never saw her do this! I...
她没告诉我, 我也没见过她干过！我...
She did borrow my handkerchief.
她的确借走了我的手绢
Where were you then?
那时你们在哪里？
By that pile of seeds.
在那堆种子旁边
Yes you sh, you see, she's got it on her hands!
是的, 你看, 她把那个拿到手上了！
And she rubbed it off on your handkerchief!
然后她用你的手绢把它擦掉了！
Oh... Why didn't she tell us?!
哦...为什么她不告诉我们！
You can help her, can't you Doctor?
你能帮她的吧, 是吗, 博士？
Grandfather we can do something can't we?
爷爷, 我们可以做点什么吧？
What happened? D-did I..?
发生了什么？我是不是...?
You fainted, that's all.
你晕倒了, 仅此而已
The insecticide... Is that why I feel like this?
杀虫剂...那就是我感觉糟糕的原因吗？
Yes. You got some of it on your hands
and you didn't us tell anything about it!
是的, 你的手上沾到了, 而你什么都不告诉我们！
It was very wrong of you, wasn't it?
你这样是完全错误的, 是不是！
Am I... Am I?
是吗...是吗？
No-no-no, this little attack...
experience is only temporary.
不不不, 它作用不大, 过一会儿就好了
- Oh take it easy Barbara,
- It'll pass
- 放松一点  - 会过去的
Come on, take it easy
来吧, 别紧张
Well what can we do for her?
我们能帮她做点什么？
Well it's urgent that
we get her back to normal size,
要紧的是我们得让她恢复到正常大小
but, ah, at the moment her
protective cells are too small
但在当前, 她的防卫细胞太小了
to cope with the molecules
of poison in her bloodstream.
不足以对付她血液里面的毒药分子
But if we can, that dosage of insecticide
will be seventy times less dangerous,
但如果我们能还原, 这些剂量的杀虫剂, 危害就会降低70倍
- practically nothing at all!
- Are you sure?
- 基本上就没事了  - 你确定吗？
Yes I'm quite sure. But we
must get her back to the ship.
是的我很确定. 但我们必须把她弄回飞船去
What are we waiting for?
那我们还等什么？
How are you feeling?
你感觉怎么样了？
Ooh..a bit ropey. Ooh, could
do with a glass of water.
噢, 不是太好. 嗯, 想喝一杯水
We're going to take you back to the ship.
我们打算带你回飞船去
Alright, just give me a minute.
好吧, 但给我一分钟
Come on Barbara, we've got a long way to go.
加油芭芭拉, 我们有好长一段路要走
You can get us back to normal size?
你能把我们变回正常大小吗？
Oho, yes! of course I can
dear boy, yes, course I can...
哦, 是的！当然我能, 亲爱的小伙子, 当然我能
I hope.
但愿是
We've got to repeat exactly wha..the
things that happened to us when we landed.
我们要严格重复...我们着陆时所发生的事情
Is there anything I can do?
有什么我可以干的吗？
Yes, that seed over there by the chair.
Take it over to the table
有, 那个椅子边的那颗种子, 把它拿到桌子上去
so that we can all see it.
And wrap that round it when you do it.
这样我们都能看到它. 拿的时候要把它包住
Doctor!
博士！
Doctor I...
博士我...
Shh-sh. I think it's working.
Splendid, I think it's working, my boy!
嘘, 我觉得起作用了. 很棒, 我觉得起作用了, 孩子！
Doctor, look at that seed!
博士, 看那个种子！
Yes yes, we've done it!
Yes, ha-ha ha-ha, we've done it, yes!
是的是的, 我们搞定了！是的, 哈哈哈, 我们搞定了, 嘢！
Doctor, it's incredible,
that seed, it's completely vanished!
博士, 不可思议啊, 那个种子, 完全消失了！
No no my dear boy, no. Hah-ha!
不, 不, 亲爱的小伙子, 不是, 哈哈！
Look, can you see, it hasn't vanished at all!
看, 看到了吗, 它完全没有消失！
Grandfather, is that the seed
you brought in with you?
爷爷, 那就是你带进来的那粒种子吗？
The same seed!
同一颗种子！
Then we are back to normal!
那我们回到正常了！
Completely my dear!
完全是, 亲爱的！
Now before I check up and see where we are,
现在在我检查完并看清我们在哪里之前
I suggest you all go and have a good scrub mm?
我建议你们都去好好洗漱一番, 嗯？
Go-on, off you go!
去吧, 你们走吧
Oh dear-dear-dear-dear-dear,
now isn't that irritating mm?!
哦, 天啊天啊天啊, 这不是让人恼火吗？
I had to repair that wretched thing
and now look at it, I can't see a thing!
我还得修这个破玩意儿, 现在看看, 什么都看不到！
（请看下集: 《Dalek 入侵地球》）
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)